## LYDIA NEWMAN-HEGGIE

Minneapolis, MN 55414

Phone: 612-396-9229 | Email: Inewmanheggie@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/lydia-newman-heggie-b2738bb0/ GitHub: https://github.com/lnewmanheggie | Portfolio: lydianewmanheggie.com

#### SUMMARY

Software developer creating sleek, intuitive user experiences with powerful capabilities. Graduate of the University of Minnesota coding bootcamp. Interested in the logic and functionality side of applications, and working with data. BA in studio art from Oberlin College.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, PHP, Codelgniter, Express, React, jQuery, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, AWS, MVC framework, REST APIs, HTML, CSS, Git, Jest, Adobe creative suite, design

#### **PROJECTS**

### FRIENDS SCHOOL OF MN PLANT SALE DATABASE | https://github.com/fsmn/plantsale

- Currently volunteering to help refactor code for the website which organizes the largest plant sale in the midwest. Friends School of MN uses this plant sale as a way to fundraise to provide scholarships to students.
- Project is built in the PHP framework Codelgniter and uses a MySQL database, which is implemented using Docker.
- Duties involve writing and refactoring PHP and JavaScript code to fix bugs, add enhancements, and improve readability. Using Github to manage workflow.

# BUSI-MAN | https://github.com/Inewmanheggie/Busi-Man https://busi-man.herokuapp.com/

- Worked in a group to create a web application for small businesses to keep track of employees, inventory, and sales all in one place.
- Built using React, Node.js, Express.js, and MongoDB.
- Main contributions:
  - o Implemented a barcode scanner which allowed users to scan an item on their phone and add to inventory or make a sale. Utilized the Scan to Web phone app for the barcode scanner and configured the scanner with React to save the numeric barcode value in the database.
  - Implemented the login/signup feature and authentication using JWT, which was created on the back-end at each login and expired after 30 minutes. JWT was stored in local storage and checked for expiration at each attempt to send data or navigate to a new page.

## CRIME TRACKER | https://infinite-savannah-89804.herokuapp.com/ https://github.com/mesgt/charmeleon

- Full-stack web application that allowed users to view crime data for different states and the city of Denver, as well as enter their own crime data.
- Build using Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, and Handlebars.
- Main contributions:

- Map 1: Used Google maps API to render a map with geoJSON data and create clickable outlines of US states. Crime data for each state was sourced from FBI and U.S. census APIs and was available to users in a graph when they clicked on a state.
- Map 2: Used Google maps API along with crime data from a MySQL database to render pins on a map based on lat and lon. Allowed users to see where crimes were being committed in Denver.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## TEACHER | 11/2019 - 12/2020 | Snapology, Minneapolis, MN

• Lead classes for k-8 students related to STEM and robotics, created lessons and improved lesson plans.

Key Accomplishment: Designed the 2021 summer camp brochure

## ACT TUTOR | 9/2019 - 7/2020 | Huntington Learning Center, Blaine, MN

 Prepared high school students for the ACT in all subjects, and tailored curriculum to meet individual student needs.

Key Accomplishment: Helped students improve scores up to 11 points.

## MEDICATION SPECIALIST | 9/2018 - 12/2019 | Wayside Recovery Center, Minneapolis, MN

• Supported women in addiction recovery and administered meds, including narcotics.

Key Accomplishments: Obtained CNA (certified nursing assistant) and TMA (trained medication aide) certification.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Bootcamp Certificate** | 12/2020 - 3/2021 | University of Minnesota, St. Paul, MN A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express.js, and React.

BA Degree (fine arts): Oberlin College, Oberlin, OH